<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <system>Firefox</system>
  <issues>
    <issue>
      <id>200001</id>
      <title>Rewrite nsMsgDBView::GetLevelInUnreadView</title>
      <description>So i ended up in an infinite loop in nsMsgDBView::GetLevelInUnreadView

I couldn't figure out what the function was doing, so i rewrote it.

that made it at least comprehensible, and then dmose suggested that 
     m_db-&gt;GetMsgHdrForKey(parentKey, getter_AddRefs(curMsgHdr));
was probably failing.

he was right.</description>
      <attachments>
        <attach>rewrite</attach>
        <attach>as before, removes dead code including levelStack</attach>
        <attach>-w</attach>
      </attachments>
    </issue>
    <issue>
      <id>200002</id>
      <title>bookmarks.js :  missing semicolon in line #98 ?</title>
      <description>User-Agent:       Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Win98; en-US; rv:1.4a) Gecko/20030329
Build Identifier: Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Win98; en-US; rv:1.4a) Gecko/20030329

http://lxr.mozilla.org/seamonkey/source/xpfe/components/bookmarks/resources/bookmarks.js#95

74 function initServices()
...
 
 95   kPREFContractID  = "@mozilla.org/preferences-service;1";
 96   kPREFIID         = Components.interfaces.nsIPrefService;
 97   PREF             = Components.classes[kPREFContractID].getService(kPREFIID)
 98                                .getBranch(null)
 99 
100   kSOUNDContractID = "@mozilla.org/sound;1";
101   kSOUNDIID        = Components.interfaces.nsISound;
102   SOUND            =
Components.classes[kSOUNDContractID].createInstance(kSOUNDIID);
103 

Reproducible: Always

Steps to Reproduce:





If it was C, I would tell there is a ; missing, but it isn´t C.</description>
      <attachments>
        <attach>Patch</attach>
        <attach>updated patch</attach>
      </attachments>
    </issue>
    <issue>
      <id>200003</id>
      <title>Form fails to display on page</title>
      <description>User-Agent:       Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Win98; en-US; rv:1.3) Gecko/20030312
Build Identifier: Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Win98; en-US; rv:1.3) Gecko/20030312

A page required to set up a new meeting does not display properly.  All the form
fields are missing with Mozilla 1.3 but they display properly with IE6.

Reproducible: Always

Steps to Reproduce:
1.Requires a login so I can't give you a url but it always fails.
2.
3.

Actual Results:  
I will attach the source for a page that displays a bar with "New Meeting" on
the top, followed by some empty white space followed by a bar with 3 buttons
"Create", "Cancel" and "Help".  The cancel and help button work as they should,
but the Create button requires a form to be filled in, but that form does not
display.

Expected Results:  
A form that allows some information to be entered regarding the time, place and
description of a meeting is displayed when the page is accessed by IE 6.</description>
      <attachments>
        <attach>Form that loads successfully into IE but fails to display boxes in Mozilla 1.3</attach>
      </attachments>
    </issue>
    <issue>
      <id>200004</id>
      <title>"match only previously typed sites" autocomplete pref doesn't work     (type in location bar and nothing is matched)</title>
      <description>found using 2003.03.31 on all platforms. not sure if this pref ever worked.

1. go to the Smart Browsing pref panel and make sure the checkbox for
"Automatically complete text typed in the Location bar" is enabled.

2. click on the Advanced button.

3. make sure these three options are enabled (checked):

a. "autcomplete best match as you type"
b. "show list of matching results"
c. "match only websites you've typed previously"

4. click OK, OK to save and dismiss prefs.

5. open a new browser window.

6. go to the urlbar and enter supersnail.com.

7. once that site loads, click on a link or two.

8. close that window and open another one.

9. go to the urlbar and start typing supersnail.com...

expected: due to (a), autcomplete should prefill "supersnail.com" in the urlbar.
due to (b) a droplist should also appear that contains "supersnail.com". and,
because of (c), the other links visited at supersnail.com should not appear at all.

actual results: neither prefilling of the urlbar nor an autocomplete droplist
appear at all.</description>
      <attachments>
        <attach>Fix</attach>
      </attachments>
    </issue>
    <issue>
      <id>200005</id>
      <title>pk12util displays the user's password in plain text, twice</title>
      <description>Observe the following output from a run of the pk12util utility, reported in
the n.p.m.crypto newsgroup:

&gt; &gt;&gt;pk12util -i "my.p12" -d "my directory" -v
&gt; &gt;
&gt; &gt; Enter Password or Pin for "NSS Certificate DB": *****
&gt; &gt; Enter password for PKCS12 file: *****
&gt; &gt; Converted from:
&gt; &gt; 73 77 61 6d 70 66 6f 78 31 31  0
&gt; &gt; Converted to:
&gt; &gt;  0 73  0 77  0 61  0 6d  0 70  0 66  0 6f  0 78  0 31  0 31  0  0 

Those last 4 lines show the user's password twice, once in UTF-8 and 
a second time in UCS-2.  This serves no useful purpose, and is a security
flaw.  The code that prints those 4 lines of output should be removed.</description>
      <attachments>
        <attach>ifdef out offending code and remove some dead code.</attach>
      </attachments>
    </issue>
    <issue>
      <id>200006</id>
      <title>cannot dismiss alert when accessing a bogus url via open web location (target=current window or new tab, new window works fine)</title>
      <description>found using 2003.03.31.03 comm bits on mac 10.2.4. not a problem on win2k or
linux. this is a recent regression, as it works fine in the 2003.03.25.03 build.

1. bring up the Open Web Location dialog (cmd+shift+L).
2. select "New Navigator Tab" from the droplist.
3. enter a bogus url in the location textfield (eg, foo.foo.foo).
4. click the Open button.
5. you'll get an alert (sheet) saying that the url is invalid --click OK to
dismiss the alert.

results: the alert sheet won't go away. with the exception of the apple and
application menu, the entire menubar is disabled. you can only quit the app.</description>
      <attachments>
        <attach>Sampler data showing stacks for thread deadlock</attach>
        <attach>proposed fix, plus comment cleanup</attach>
      </attachments>
    </issue>
    <issue>
      <id>200007</id>
      <title>add option to flush ldapsearch output after each entry</title>
      <description>Currently, when attempting to capture the output to a file, of a persistent
search when using ldapsearch with the -C option, ldapsearch uses block buffering
of output, instead of line buffering. This means that at least 8192 bytes of
data need to be sent to the output before it is flushed out. 

It would be very helpful if there was an option to cause ldapsearch to perform
line buffering of output, so that every line of output was flushed.</description>
      <attachments>
        <attach>proposed fix</attach>
        <attach>revised fix: add an option for this (-r)</attach>
        <attach>final fix</attach>
      </attachments>
    </issue>
    <issue>
      <id>200008</id>
      <title>Can not display local directory/files properly</title>
      <description>Build: 03-31 trunk build / Mac 10.2.4

Steps to reproduce:
1. Create some non-ascii directory/file names under &lt;OS X&gt;.
2. Launch browser and open a file under &lt;OS X&gt; or a non-ascii directory.

Result:
The non-ascii characters are not displayed correctly no matter what charset you
select.

Note: 
- if you open a file or directory under &lt;OS X&gt;, the &lt;OS X&gt; is not showed in URL
bar, it always show as file:///&lt;file or directory name&gt;.
- IE, Safari have different behavior when open local file, so this problem not
reproduce there.
- It also can not reproduce on N7.02 because the behavior is different too.</description>
      <attachments>
        <attach>
screen shot for an example
            </attach>
      </attachments>
    </issue>
    <issue>
      <id>200009</id>
      <title>classic privacy dialog icon is a modern picture</title>
      <description>actual results, picture looks like:
http://lxr.mozilla.org/seamonkey/source/extensions/cookie/resources/skin/modern/status-cookie.gif

expected results, a picture of classic with that widget.</description>
      <attachments>
        <attach>
newclassic
            </attach>
        <attach>
Classic status-cookie.gif
            </attach>
      </attachments>
    </issue>
    <issue>
      <id>200010</id>
      <title>plain-text editor mangles blank lines</title>
      <description>User-Agent:       Mozilla/5.0 (X11; U; Linux i686; en-US; rv:1.3) Gecko/20030312
Build Identifier: Mozilla/5.0 (X11; U; Linux i686; en-US; rv:1.3) Gecko/20030312

this bug report will suck because i can't reproduce it, yet it happens
all the time.

1) after sending a spanking new plain-text message, many of the
blank lines that separate my paragraphs are lost.  i know this
because i receive a copy of the message.  i believe the mangling
isn't done by an MTA because the copy of the message in my 'Sent'
folder appears the same as the copy I received from the MTA.

2) if i "edit as new" one of these received, mangled messages, the
line ends and spacing are changed even more.

note that my mail store is a lotus notes IMAP instance (shudder, yes,
i'm in hell and i know it).  note also that this happens when
i've set the wrap length to 0 (for displayed messages) and for
the wrap length set to 1,000.  

Reproducible: Sometimes

Steps to Reproduce:
1.
2.
3.



Expected Results:  
honor my blank lines and line lengths.

just tell me i'm not insane and i'll go away.</description>
      <attachments/>
    </issue>
  </issues>
</root>
